<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.4.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://blockinfo.de/en/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://blockinfo.de/en/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2017-08-05T13:46:13+00:00</updated><id>https://blockinfo.de/en/</id><title type="html">Blockinfo.de</title><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title type="html">What is Ethereum?</title><link href="https://blockinfo.de/en/article/ethereum/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is Ethereum?" /><published>2017-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://blockinfo.de/en/article/ethereum</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blockinfo.de/en/article/ethereum/">&lt;p&gt;Ethereum is developed in 2015 by Vitalik Buterin as a platform for digital contracts. In Ethereum included is the &lt;a href=&quot;/en/article/cryptocurrencies&quot;&gt;Cryptocurrency&lt;/a&gt; “Ether”. Ether can be used to do financial transactions, like in other cryptocurrencies. Ethereum is to this day, the second biggest cryptocurrency. But Ethereum has some interesting and important advantages over &lt;a href=&quot;/en/article/bitcoin&quot;&gt;Bitcoin&lt;/a&gt;. When the project around Ethereum started, it recieved around 18 Mio. Dollar in crowdfunded capital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;important-data&quot;&gt;Important data&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Name&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;   Ethereum (ETH)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Year&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;   2015&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Smalles Unit&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;   0,000000000000000001 ETH (17 Nullen)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Blocktime&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;   12 Sekunden&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Available/Total&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;   93.5 Mio. / No Limitation&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Website&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;   &lt;a href=&quot;https://ethereum.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.ethereum.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following data are from the website &lt;a href=&quot;https://coinmarketcap.com/currencies/ethereum/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Coinmarketcap&lt;/a&gt;
and represent the current value of one Ether in Euro, the rank, the market cap and the 24h trading volume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot; src=&quot;https://files.coinmarketcap.com/static/widget/currency.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;coinmarketcap-currency-widget&quot; data-currency=&quot;ethereum&quot; data-base=&quot;EUR&quot; data-secondary=&quot;&quot; data-ticker=&quot;true&quot; data-rank=&quot;true&quot; data-marketcap=&quot;true&quot; data-volume=&quot;true&quot; data-stats=&quot;EUR&quot; data-statsticker=&quot;false&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;design&quot;&gt;Design&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ethereum is based on a Blockchain and is used to do digital contracts, also called “Smart Contracts”. Similar to &lt;a href=&quot;/en/article/bitcoin&quot;&gt;Bitcoin&lt;/a&gt;, Ethereum doesn’t need any central administration or bank. Ethereum is not only focussed on returning the control about financial transactions back to us, but also on contracts.
Every user of Ethereum has his own public adress, which he can pass on to recieve Ether for example. The secret, private key is used to send transactions or to sign contracts, similar to a signature on a document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is how a public Ethereum adress looks like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;168bc315a2er09052d83d1c5811n533620031f67
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ether can be split up into smaller parts, to make transactions more precise. It is possible to send only half of an Ether or a quarter. The smallest possible unit is 0.000000000000000001 Ether and is called “Wei”. Therefore every Ether can be split up in 1000000000000000000 (one trillion) Wei.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;smart-contracts&quot;&gt;Smart Contracts&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Smart Contract is used to make secure and fast contracts between to partys, without a real signature or a complicated process on paper. Even more important, there is no central administration of these contracts and no third party is making profit out of this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Blockchain of Ethereum is not only capeable to store transaction, but also small computer programms which can check certain conditions and execute instructions. An example would be a contract about a licensed software, which is only valid when a monthly payment is made to a specific account.
There are many of other applications of the Smart Contracts of Ethereum, like the energy-supply and its accounting, publishing and paying for apps or as a safe payment for other services. Another important application is to store our private data more secure and trustful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ethereum is designed with the technology of Smart Contracts not only to solve a lot of problems of today, but also to solve some of the future problems. The flexibility and the possibility to extend the Blockchain with small programms is the foundation for this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;mining&quot;&gt;Mining&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The calculation of new blocks in the Ethereum network needs a lot of computational power. Everyone who is using their onw computer to support the system is getting rewarded with Ether. The mining reward of Ethereum is 5 Ether for every new block. The blocktime, the time to calculate a new block, is with 10-15sec a lot faster than Bitcoin.
Ethereum has no limitation of total units. In the future the Ethereum-network has to increase the difficulty of the calculations to ensure the stability of the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;features&quot;&gt;Features&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ethereum as a platform for Smart Contracts has a lot more potential for the future than only &lt;a href=&quot;/en/article/cryptocurrencies&quot;&gt;Cryptocurrencies&lt;/a&gt; like Bitcoin.
Ethereum is not only a currency, a tool to manage financial transactions, but more a platform which offers a lot of solutions to future problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;downsides&quot;&gt;Downsides&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ethereum is a lot newer than &lt;a href=&quot;/en/article/bitcoin&quot;&gt;Bitcoin&lt;/a&gt; and the future developement of Ethereum is not completely clear.
With more possibilities of extension, are coming more problems to the platform. A bug in the Smart Contracts in June 2016 was the cause for a lot of Ether beeing destroyed. The network fixed the bug, but decided to split the project into two projects. Ethereum which is beeing continued as the main project and “Ethereum Classic” which is not supported by the developers anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-can-i-get-ether&quot;&gt;How can I get Ether?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first you have to create your own Ether-account, a “Ether-Wallet”. After that, Ether can be bought from websites like &lt;a href=&quot;https://anycoindirect.eu/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.anycoindirect.eu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another way would be to use your computer to join a mining-network. Everyone who shares their computer to mine new Ether will be rewarded. But usually the low performance and the low efficiency of personal computers is not even worth all the energy costs.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Leonard Thiele</name></author><summary type="html">Ethereum is developed in 2015 by Vitalik Buterin as a platform for digital contracts. In Ethereum included is the Cryptocurrency “Ether”. Ether can be used to do financial transactions, like in other cryptocurrencies. Ethereum is to this day, the second biggest cryptocurrency. But Ethereum has some interesting and important advantages over Bitcoin. When the project around Ethereum started, it recieved around 18 Mio. Dollar in crowdfunded capital.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What is Bitcoin?</title><link href="https://blockinfo.de/en/article/bitcoin/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is Bitcoin?" /><published>2017-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://blockinfo.de/en/article/bitcoin</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blockinfo.de/en/article/bitcoin/">&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin is the first real &lt;a href=&quot;/en/article/cryptocurrencies&quot;&gt;Cryptocurrency&lt;/a&gt; and was published by Satoshi Nakamoto (Pseudonym) in 2009. Bitcoin is the first and most well known cryptocurrency, therefore it is used the most and is the reference for all other currencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;important-data&quot;&gt;Important data&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Name&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;   Bitcoin (BTC)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Year&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;   2009&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Smallest unit&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;   0.00000001 BTC (7 Zeros)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Blocktime&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;   10min&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Available/Total&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;   16.5 Mio. / 21 Mio.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Website&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bitcoin.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.bitcoin.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following data are from the website &lt;a href=&quot;https://coinmarketcap.com/currencies/bitcoin/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Coinmarketcap&lt;/a&gt;
and represent the current value of one Bitcoin in Euro, the rank, the market cap and the 24h trading volume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot; src=&quot;https://files.coinmarketcap.com/static/widget/currency.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;coinmarketcap-currency-widget&quot; data-currency=&quot;bitcoin&quot; data-base=&quot;EUR&quot; data-secondary=&quot;&quot; data-ticker=&quot;true&quot; data-rank=&quot;true&quot; data-marketcap=&quot;true&quot; data-volume=&quot;true&quot; data-stats=&quot;EUR&quot; data-statsticker=&quot;false&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;desgin&quot;&gt;Desgin&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin’s foundation is a Blockchain and the general purpose is to make digital payments. Every user has his own Bitcoin-adress and can send his Bitcoins to other people in the network.
Once a transaction is made, it can never be reverted or manipulated again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every Bitcoin-user is basicly anonymous but this anonymity is partly lost, when someone can associate a person to a public adress. The whole blockchain is completely public, so everyone can look into it and see how many coins belong to an adress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is how a public Bitcoin adress looks like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;12UwLL7Krhg3QfPqBUoKofHmHQ4wMtjpM
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make transactions more flexible, one Bitcoin can be split up into smaller parts, like a cent in Euro. The smallest possible unit is 0.00000001 Bitcoin and is called “Satoshi”. Therefore every Bitcoin can be split up in 100000000 Satoshis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;mining&quot;&gt;Mining&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The verification of new transactions and the calculation of new blocks is called “mining”. Every new calculated Block extends the blockchain of bitcoin.
Everyone who uses their computer to calculate new blocks is rewarded with new bitcoins. Since Juli 2016 the mining-revenue is 12.5 Bitcoin per block. But the workload of the calculations is so high, that you usually join a network of computers to increase the calculation-power. This is the reason why everyone on the network is only getting a part from the 12.5 Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;features&quot;&gt;Features&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin is the most known &lt;a href=&quot;/en/article/cryptocurrencies&quot;&gt;Cryptocurrency&lt;/a&gt; today, which is the reason why Bitcoin is the most accepted Cryptocurrency. Almost everyone who accepts Cryptocurrencies is accepting Bitcoin.
In addition Bitcoin has the biggest community and has the most developed network. This makes Bitcoin the most important Cryptocurreny today.
The technology behind Bitcoin is publicly available which serves as a foundation of many other currencies as Litecoin, Peercoin or many others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;downsides&quot;&gt;Downsides&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin is only a network for financial transactions. Other currencies like &lt;a href=&quot;/en/article/ethereum&quot;&gt;Ethereum&lt;/a&gt;, can also be used for many other purposes and future developements other than only the financial sector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The usual blocktime, the time needed to calculate a new block, is 10min within the Bitcoin-networt. This is, compared to other currencies, too slow and creates some problems. With more and more transactions are coming into the network, this will slow it down even more. One problem of this is, that it would be difficult to pay in a store, when every transaction is taking that much time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-can-i-get-bitcoin&quot;&gt;How can I get Bitcoin?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first you have to create your own Bitcoin-account, a “Bitcoin-Wallet”. After that, Bitcoins can be bought from websites like &lt;a href=&quot;https://anycoindirect.eu/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.anycoindirect.eu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another way would be to use your computer to join a mining-network. Everyone who shares their computer to mine new Bitcoins will be rewarded. But usually the low performance and the low efficiency of personal computers is not even worth all the energy costs.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Leonard Thiele</name></author><summary type="html">Bitcoin is the first real Cryptocurrency and was published by Satoshi Nakamoto (Pseudonym) in 2009. Bitcoin is the first and most well known cryptocurrency, therefore it is used the most and is the reference for all other currencies.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What is a cryptocurrency?</title><link href="https://blockinfo.de/en/article/cryptocurrencies/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is a cryptocurrency?" /><published>2017-07-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://blockinfo.de/en/article/cryptocurrencies</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blockinfo.de/en/article/cryptocurrencies/">&lt;p&gt;Cryptocurrencies such as &lt;a href=&quot;/en/article/bitcoin&quot;&gt;Bitcoin&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;/en/article/ethereum&quot;&gt;Ethereum&lt;/a&gt; gain increasing importance and almost everyone has heard the terms somewhere. Cryptocurrency systems offer the possibility to revolutionize the existing financial systems and create a real value behind a currency again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;cryptocurrency&quot;&gt;Cryptocurrency&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Cryptocurrency is quite simply a digital currency. The word “crypto” refers to the cryptography, the science around the encryption of information. You can make payments with Cryptocurrencies, just like with other currencies. If you want to buy something and the seller accepts those currencies, you can simply transfer the required price to his digital account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-the-difference-to-traditional-currencies-like-euro&quot;&gt;What is the difference to traditional currencies, like Euro?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no finacial institutes, no third party who manages our account and then transfers the money. At most cryptocurrencies, we are the “bank”, computers distributed all around the world, calculate our referrals and maintain a persistent list. This list of past referrals, also referred as blockchain, is the most important innovation in cryptocurrency system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/article/cryptocurrencies/bitcoin-transactions.png&quot; alt=&quot;Bitcoin transactions&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;blockchain&quot;&gt;Blockchain&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “blockchain” contains all the transfers ever made, collected in blocks. A block is a collection of transactions. With &lt;a href=&quot;/en/article/bitcoin&quot;&gt;Bitcoin&lt;/a&gt; for example, one block contains 2400 transactions. Every block contains some more information, like the digital and unique “fingerprint” of his predecessor. Once a block is full and once completed, it can never be changed again, because his unique fingerprint would change. This provides the very high security to cryptocurrency transfers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/article/cryptocurrencies/cryptocurrencies_block.png&quot; alt=&quot;Blockchain easy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;my-account&quot;&gt;My account&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As explained, Cryptocurrencies do not need a finacial institutes, so you do not need to log in or create an account to an institute for their management. This is the reason why many cryptocurrency transfers are also completely anonymous. What you have to do is just create your own account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to create a new account, you can easily do this with so-called “wallets”. A wallet is nothing more than a computer program, which gives you access to the selected currency. When you create an account, two keys are created. One of these keys is the public address that can be passed to receive referrals, similar to a conto number. The second key is secret and may never be passed on. It is the key with which you can send referrals yourself. Similar to the PIN of a bank card. The one Who owns this private key is also the owner of the account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to know how much money you have just available, you simply open your wallet. This program then goes through the entire list and calculates all past referrals and shows me my result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-is-new-money-generated&quot;&gt;How is new money generated?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If, for example, Europe wants to produce new Euros, the European Central Bank can set a certain sum and integrate it into the existing financial system without any real equivalent. Even banks have long been no longer with real countervalues. This is different with cryptocurrencies! All money has a direct value, namely the work of a computer. The calculation time of a computer creates a real value to every created unit. New cryptocurrency units are given to anyone who makes their computer available for calculating new blocks. This process is called “mining”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, a lot of cryptocurrencies are already limited in their maximal circulating amount. For example, there can never be more than 21 Million &lt;a href=&quot;/en/article/bitcoin&quot;&gt;Bitcoin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, a rapid depreciation of money within a cryptocurrency is much less possible than with the established financial systems and thus guarantees a high stability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;when-can-i-pay-with-cryptocurrencies&quot;&gt;When can I pay with cryptocurrencies?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The developement of Bitcoin started in 2008 and improved a lot since then. Cryptocurrencies are getting more and more media attention and relevance in the everyday life. Every day there are more online shops accepting the new currencies, but also local stores started to accept them as a payment.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Leonard Thiele</name></author><summary type="html">Cryptocurrencies such as Bitcoin or Ethereum gain increasing importance and almost everyone has heard the terms somewhere. Cryptocurrency systems offer the possibility to revolutionize the existing financial systems and create a real value behind a currency again. Cryptocurrency A Cryptocurrency is quite simply a digital currency. The word “crypto” refers to the cryptography, the science around the encryption of information. You can make payments with Cryptocurrencies, just like with other currencies. If you want to buy something and the seller accepts those currencies, you can simply transfer the required price to his digital account. What is the difference to traditional currencies, like Euro? There is no finacial institutes, no third party who manages our account and then transfers the money. At most cryptocurrencies, we are the “bank”, computers distributed all around the world, calculate our referrals and maintain a persistent list. This list of past referrals, also referred as blockchain, is the most important innovation in cryptocurrency system. Blockchain The “blockchain” contains all the transfers ever made, collected in blocks. A block is a collection of transactions. With Bitcoin for example, one block contains 2400 transactions. Every block contains some more information, like the digital and unique “fingerprint” of his predecessor. Once a block is full and once completed, it can never be changed again, because his unique fingerprint would change. This provides the very high security to cryptocurrency transfers. My account As explained, Cryptocurrencies do not need a finacial institutes, so you do not need to log in or create an account to an institute for their management. This is the reason why many cryptocurrency transfers are also completely anonymous. What you have to do is just create your own account. If you want to create a new account, you can easily do this with so-called “wallets”. A wallet is nothing more than a computer program, which gives you access to the selected currency. When you create an account, two keys are created. One of these keys is the public address that can be passed to receive referrals, similar to a conto number. The second key is secret and may never be passed on. It is the key with which you can send referrals yourself. Similar to the PIN of a bank card. The one Who owns this private key is also the owner of the account. If you want to know how much money you have just available, you simply open your wallet. This program then goes through the entire list and calculates all past referrals and shows me my result. How is new money generated? If, for example, Europe wants to produce new Euros, the European Central Bank can set a certain sum and integrate it into the existing financial system without any real equivalent. Even banks have long been no longer with real countervalues. This is different with cryptocurrencies! All money has a direct value, namely the work of a computer. The calculation time of a computer creates a real value to every created unit. New cryptocurrency units are given to anyone who makes their computer available for calculating new blocks. This process is called “mining”. In addition, a lot of cryptocurrencies are already limited in their maximal circulating amount. For example, there can never be more than 21 Million Bitcoin. Thus, a rapid depreciation of money within a cryptocurrency is much less possible than with the established financial systems and thus guarantees a high stability. When can I pay with cryptocurrencies? The developement of Bitcoin started in 2008 and improved a lot since then. Cryptocurrencies are getting more and more media attention and relevance in the everyday life. Every day there are more online shops accepting the new currencies, but also local stores started to accept them as a payment.</summary></entry></feed>